REIS HALEEM

, Columbus, OH 43202 | (C)

haleem.9@osu.edu

Professional Summary

I am a highly motivated person, and I am always looking for new ways to improve myself. With my experience in being a Teaching Assistant, I have learned effective communication techniques that lead to growth, as well as how to develop a healthy working environment with others. Over the past 3 years, I have been able to develop a sound coding style, and have developed an eagerness to learn new languages and improve my own skill. I am seeking a summer internship that involves elements of computer science.

Experience

First Year Engineering Teaching Assistant

08/2017 to Current

The Ohio State University - Columbus, OH

Currently employed by the Engineering Education Department of The Ohio State University. This heavily involves working in a team and helping new students with fundamental concepts of engineering, as well as learning how to effectively build relationships with students to help them learn in a healthy environment.

Computer Science Teaching Assistant

05/2017 to 09/2017

The Ohio State University - Columbus, OH

Currently employed by the Computer Science Department of The Ohio State University as an Undergraduate Teaching Assistant. The course consists of learning Java, computer science concepts, and introducing students to good programming practices.

Kiwanis Club Member 08/2014 to 08/2016

Dublin Kiwanis International - Dublin, Ohio

Participated in community volunteer opportunities such as the Dublin Irish Festival, and as a member of Kiwanis, connected with many people and organized volunteer opportunities, while recruiting people to participate, teaching valuable communication techniques.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science and Engineering

2020

The Ohio State University - Columbus, OH

- Plans to specialize in Artificial Intelligence, as well as interested in web security
- Cumulative GPA: 3.345, Major GPA: 3.7

Projects

Advanced Energy Vehicle (AEV)

- Used Arduino code to move an AEV along a track and picking up cargo
- More on the project: https://u.osu.edu/engr118232466 spr2017 groupl/

Skills

- Intermediate: Java and using Java to complete projects
- Beginner/Learning: MATLAB, Python, C#, HTML
- Proficient understanding of good coding practices
- Experience with testing and improving code
- Excellent in group settings and taking the lead if necessary
- Excellent technical writer